這堿O博克島
This is Berk
有像北極那樣12天絕望的嚴寒 也有南極酷冷的垂死之感
It's 12 days North of hopeless and a few degrees South of freezing to death.
島就坐落在"悲劇子午線"上
It's located solidly on the Meridian of Misery.
這就是我的家鄉 簡而言之: 一成不變
My village. In a word: sturdy.
現在這堿O第七代人了 但是房子都還很新
It's been here for seven generations but every single building is new.
我們打漁 打獵 還可以欣賞迷人的夕陽
We have fishing, hunting, and a charming view of the sunsets.
唯一的問題是害蟲
The only problems are the pests.
一般來說 害蟲都是老鼠或是蚊子
You see, most places have mice or mosquitoes.
但我們的是
We have...
龍
Dragons.
大多數人選擇離開 但是不是我們
Most people would leave, but not us.
我們是維京人
We're Vikings.
我們擁有頑強
We stubbornness issues.
我叫Hiccup
My name is Hiccup.
我知道不是什麼偉大的名字 但是也不是最糟的
Great name, I know. But it's not the worst.
父母們相信一個難聽的名字可以驅趕地精和惡魔
Parents believe a hideous name will frighten off Gnomes and Trolls.
好像我們維京勇士的壯舉還不如一個名字
Like our charming Viking demeanor wouldn't do that.
早
'Morning.
你在這堸竣偵? 進去!
What are you doing here? Get inside!
快回去!
Get back inside!
Hiccup! 你又出來幹什麼  你出來幹什麼? 回去!
Hiccup! What is he doing out again... What are you doing out? Get inside!
這是大塊頭Stoick 部落的首領
That's Stoick the Vast, Chief of the tribe.
他們說他還是嬰兒的時候 他就能把龍頭從它的脖子上扭下來
They say that when he was a baby he popped a Dragon's head clean off its shoulders.
我相信嗎? 當然信
Do I believe it? Yes, I do.
有哪些龍?
What have we got?
Gronckles Nadders Zipplebacks  哦 還有兇魘群龍
Gronckles, Nadders, Zipplebacks... Oh, and hordes of Monstruous Nightmares.
有沒有夜煞?
Any Night Furys?
現在還沒有   很好
None so far.   Good.
點燃火炬!
Light the torches!
哦 很高興你也來參加這樣的晚會 我還以為你被抓走了
Oh, nice of you to join the party. I thought you'd been carried off.
誰? 我? 得了吧  我肌肉太多 它們不喜歡
Who? Me? Nah, come on... I'm way too muscular for their taste.
它們不知道怎麼吃所有的  這些
They wouldn't know what to do with all... this.
好吧 它們需要牙籤 是吧?
Well, they need toothpicks, don't they?
那個脾氣暴躁 還裝著義肢的傻瓜叫Gobber
The meathead with the attitude and interchangeable hands, is Gobber.
我從小做他的學徒
I have been his apprentice ever since I was little.
嗯 比現在小一點
Well, littler
我們去空曠的地方防守 用投射器反攻
We move to the moor defenses. We'll counterattack with the catapults.
看見了嗎? 老村落 卻有很多很多新房子
See? Old village. Lots and lots of new houses.
著火了!
Fire!
哦 那是Fishlegs
Oh, and that's Fishlegs
那是Snotlout
Snotlout
雙胞胎Ruffnut和Tuffnut
The twins, Ruffnut and Tuffnut...
還有
And...
是Astrid
Astrid.
喔 他們的工作酷多了
Aww, their job is so much cooler.
哦 拜託 放我出去 我要建功!
Oh, come on. Let me out, please. I need to make my mark!
哦 你已經做了很多的貢獻了 但是都是錯誤的
Oh, you have made plenty of marks. All in the wrong places.
就兩分鐘 我會殺了一條龍的 我的人生就將從此改變
Please, 2 minutes. I'll kill a dragon. My life will get infinitely better.
我甚至能去約會
I might even get a date.
你連鎯頭都舉不起 連斧頭都揮不動
You can't lift a hammer. You can't swing an axe.
甚至這其中一個都扔不出
You can't even throw one of these.
好 好 但是這個可以幫我扔
Okay, fine, but this will throw it for me.
看見了嗎 就和我說的一樣
See, now this right here is what I'm talking about.
但是 它  它只要再稍稍校準下
But it... it's a mild calibration issue.
Hiccup 如果你想去和龍戰鬥
Hiccup, if you ever want to get out there to fight dragons
你必須改變這些
you need to stop all....
這些
this.
但是你指的是我的全身
But you just pointed to all of me.
是 就是全身
Yes, that's it.
要脫胎換骨
Stop being all of you.
哦    哦 是
Oh...   Oh, yes.
先生 您這是在玩一個危險的遊戲
You sir, are playing a dangerous game...
保持維京人這種原始的特質
keeping this much raw Vikingness contained.
後果會很嚴重!   我會承擔的
There will be consequences!   I take my chances.
去磨劍 快走!
Sword, sharpened, now!
總有一天 我會到那堛
One day I'll get out there.
因為在這 殺死龍意味著一切
Because killing a dragon is everything around here.
打倒一條Nadder至少可以讓我得到注意
A Nadderhead is sure to get me at least noticed.
Gronckles很強硬
Gronckles are tough.
打倒一條肯定可以找到一個女朋友
Taking down one of those would definitely get me a girlfriend.
一條Zippleback:
A Zippleback: ...
不太現實 兩個頭 雙倍的難度
exotic, two heads, twice the status.
他們找到羊了!
They found the sheep!
向下面集中火力!
Concentrate fire over the lower bank!
快!
Hurry up!
開火!
Fire!
還有 兇魘
And then, there's the Monstruous Nightmare.
只有最棒的維京人敢挑戰它們
Only the best Vikings go after those.
它們有一個討人厭的壞習慣 把自己點燃
They have this nasty habit of setting themselves on fire.
再次填裝!
Reload!
我可以應付
I'll take care of this.
但是最讓人覬覦的龍 還沒有人見到過
But the ultimate prize is the dragon no one's ever seen.
我們叫它
We call it the...
夜煞!   趴下!
Night Fury!   Get down!
跳!
Jump!
它從不偷東西 從不現身 然而
This thing never steals food, never shows itself, and...
從未失手
never misses.
沒人殺死過夜煞
No one has ever killed a Night Fury.
這就是我想成為第一個的原因
That's why I'm going to be the first.
守住陣地 Hiccup 他們需要我
Mind the fort, Hiccup. They need me out there.
呆著! 別動!
Stay! Put!
就這
There.
你知道我是什麼意思
You know what I mean.
Hiccup 你在幹什麼?   回來!
Hiccup, what are you doing?   Come back here!
我知道 馬上回來!
Yeah, I know, Be right back!
自己小心!
Mind yourself!
那些惡魔還有些能量
The devils still have some juice in them.
來吧
Come on.
給我些目標 給我目標
Give me something to shoot at. Give me something to shoot at.
哦! 我擊中了? 是的 我擊中了!
Oh! I hit it? Yes, I hit it!
有人看見嗎?
Did anybody see that?
除了你
Except for you.
別讓它們跑了!   好的!
Do not let them escape!   Right!
你等死吧
You're all out.
哦 還有一件事你要知道
Oh, and there's one more thing you need to know...
抱歉 爸爸
Sorry, Dad.
但是我擊中了夜煞
Okay, but I hit a Night Fury.
和上幾次不一樣 爸爸!
It's not like the last few times, Dad!
我是說 我真的擊中了
I mean, I really actually hit...
你們正在忙 我很漂亮地擊中了
You guys were busy and I had a very clear shot.
它掉在黑區 快派人過去搜
It went down just off Raven Point. Let's get a search party out there before...
閉嘴!
Stop!
給我閉嘴!
Just, stop!
你一出門 災難就降臨
Every time you step outside disaster falls.
你沒發現我還有更大的麻煩嗎?
Can you not see that I have bigger problems?
冬天臨近了 我還得餵飽全村人!
Winter is almost here and I have an entire village to feed!
看這身材差距 如果都不像你們這麼碩大 村子也可以少負擔些口糧?
Between you and me, the village could do with a little less feeding, don't you think?
這不是在開玩笑 Hiccup!
This isn't a joke, Hiccup!
你就不能老實一點?
Why can't you follow the simplest orders?
我控制不住自己 每當我看到龍 就想
I, I can't stop myself. I see a dragon and I have to just...
殺了它 爸爸 這就是我
kill it. You know, it's who I am, Dad.
哦 你可以勝任很多職責 但決不是捕龍者 Hiccup
Oh, you are many things, Hiccup, but a dragon killer is not one of them.
回到屋子堨h 確保他回去
Get back to the house. Make sure he gets there.
我還得收拾他的爛攤子
I have his mess to clean up.
演出結束了
Quite the performance.
好厲害的敗家子啊 太帥了!
I've never seen any one mess up that badly. That helped!
謝謝 謝謝 我一直在努力
Thank you. Thank you. I was trying.
我真的射中了一條   當然 Hiccup
I really did hit one.   Sure, Hiccup.
他從來不聽我說的   哎 每個家庭基本都這樣
He never listens.   Well, it runs in the family.
就算信了 也滿腹牢騷
And when he does, it's always with this disappointed scowl
就好像有人偷吃了他三明治中的肉
like someone skimped on the meat in his sandwich.
不好意思 女招待 我想你搞錯了吧
Excuse me, barmaid. I'm afraid you brought me the wrong offspring.
我要的是壯如牛的男孩 另外還得有勇氣和榮譽感
I ordered an extra large boy with beefy arms. Extra guts and glory on the side.
這個 你給我的分明是火柴棒!
This here. This is a talking fish bone!
不 你想錯了
Now, you're thinking about this all wrong.
他在乎的不是你的外表 他看重的是你的靈魂
It's not so much what you look like. It's what's inside that he can't stand.
謝謝你的總結
Thank you for summing that up.
關鍵是別強迫自己做力所不能及的事
Look, the point is, stop trying so hard to be something you're not.
我只是想和你們大夥一樣
I just want to be one of you guys.
要麼我們趕走那群龍 要麼它們消滅我們
Either we face them or they'll finish us.
想要把龍趕走只有一招
It's the only way we'll be rid of them.
如果我們找到並摧毀龍巢 它們就會離開
If we find the nest and destroy it, the dragons will leave.
它們會去別處定居
They'll find another home.
在水面凍結前 我們再搜尋一次
One more search, before the ice sets in.
以前派出的船都失蹤了
Those ships never come back.
我們是維京人 冒險是維京人的天職
We're Vikings. It's an occupational hazard.
那麼 誰和我一起去?
Now who's with me?
好吧  留下來的人照看Hiccup
Alright... Those who stay will look after Hiccup.
我去收拾行李了
I'll pack my undies.
不 我需要你留下來訓練新手
No, I need you to stay, and train some new recruits.
哦 太棒了 是的 我忙時 Hiccup可以來幫忙
Oh, perfect, yeah. And while I'm busy Hiccup can cover the store.
他負責熔鐵 磨刀 有很多時間
Molten steel, razor sharp blades, lots of time to himself...
會有什麼問題呢?
What could possibly go wrong?
我該怎麼辦呢 Gobber?
Oh, what am I going to do with him, Gobber?
讓他和其他人一起訓練
Put him in training with the others.
我是認真的   我也是
No, I'm serious.   So am I.
在你放出第一條龍之前 他就會被嚇死
He'd be killed before you let the first dragon out of its cage.
你不瞭解   我瞭解
Oh, you don't know that.   I do know that.
不 你不瞭解   我瞭解
No， you don't   No, actually, I do.
不 你不瞭解   聽我說 你知道他是怎樣的一個人
No, you don't.   Listen, you know what he's like.
從他會爬開始 我就發現他  和別人不一樣
From the time he could crawl he's been... different.
他從來不聽我的話 他寧可盯著看麻雀
He doesn't listen. He has the attention span of a sparrow.
我帶他去捕魚 他卻跑去找  巨魔!
I take him fishing and he goes hunting for... for Trolls!
真有巨魔! 它們偷了你的襪子
Trolls exist! They steal your socks.
但它們只偷左腳的 為什麼呢?
But only the left ones. What's with that?
我小的時候    哦 又來了
When I was a boy...   Oh, here we go.
我父親讓我用頭去撞石頭 我照做了
My father told me to bang my head against a rock, and I did it.
我覺得這很瘋狂 但是我沒問他為什麼
I thought it was crazy, but I didn't question him.
你猜怎麼著了?
And you know what happened?
你犯頭疼病了   石頭裂成了兩半
You got a headache.   That rock split in two.
這讓我體會到一個維京人的潛力 Gobber
It taught me what a Viking could do, Gobber.
他能撞碎山脈 夷平森林
He could crush mountains, level forests,
征服大海
tame seas!
在我還是個孩子的時候 我就知道我會變成什麼
Even as a boy I knew what I was, what I had to become...
可是Hiccup卻不能
Hiccup is not that boy.
你不能阻止他 Stoick 你只應該為他做好準備
You can't stop him, Stoick. You can only prepare him.
我知道這希望渺茫 但是你不能總是保護他
I know it seems hopeless, but the truth is you won't always be around to protect him.
他遲早會再出去 說不定就是現在
He's going to get out there again. He's probably out there now.
哦 上帝不喜歡我
Oh, the Gods hate me.
有些人會弄丟刀子 杯子
Some people lose their knife or their mug.
不 不應該是我啊! 我弄丟了一條龍
No, not me! I managed to lose an entire dragon.
嗷!
Ow!
哦 哇? 這是我  我幹的嗎? 哦 是我幹的!
Oh, wow? I... I did it? Oh, I did it!
這玩意兒真是萬能的 是的!
This fixes everything. Yes!
我放倒了一頭大野獸!
I have brought down this mighty beast!
我要殺了你 可憐的龍
I'm gonna kill you, dragon.
我會  我會切出你的心臟 交給我爸
I'm gonna... I'm gonna cut out your heart and take it to my father.
我是維京人
I'm a Viking.
我是維京人!
I'm a Viking!
是我做的
I did this.
Hiccup啊
Hiccup.
爸爸? 呃
Dad? Uh...
我有話和你說 爸爸   兒子 我也正想和你說些事
I have to talk to you, Dad.   I need to speak with you too, son.
我認為你該學習屠龍了   我不想屠龍
I think it's time you to learned to fight dragons.   I don't want to fight dragons.
什麼?   什麼?
What?   What?
你先說   還是你先說吧
Uh, you go first.   No, no, you go first.
好吧 你如願以償了
All right. You got your wish.
屠龍訓練 明早開始
Dragon training. You start in the morning.
哦 早知道我就先說了
Oh man, I should have gone first.
呃 我一直在想 你也知道 我們屠龍的人手過剩 但是
Uh, cause I was thinking. You know, we have a surplus of dragon fighting Vikings but...
後勤的人手不夠
do we have enough breadmaking Vikings, or small home repair Vikings...
你需要這個   我不想屠龍
You'll need this.   I don't want to fight dragons.
哦 來吧 你能行的   換句話說 爸爸 我殺不了龍
Oh come on, yes you do.   Rephrase. Dad, I can't kill dragons.
但是你會殺死龍的
But you will kill dragons.
不 我很確定 我不會
No, I'm really very extra sure that I won't.
是時候了 Hiccup   你沒聽我說嗎?
It's time, Hiccup.   Can you not hear me?
這事很嚴肅 兒子
This is serious, son.
當你握緊這把戰斧 你就肩負起了我們整個維京族
When you carry this axe, you carry all of us with you.
也就是說: 你能像我們一樣走路 像我們一樣講話 像我們一樣思考
Which means: You walk like us. You talk like us. You think like us.
不再如此  懦弱   你只是在對我指手畫腳
No more of... this.   You just gestured to all of me.
就這麼定了?   一直是你在自言自語
Deal?   This conversation is feeling very onesided.
就這麼定了?
Deal?
定了
Deal.
棒極了
Good.
好好訓練
Train hard.
我會回來的 大概吧
I'll be back. Probably.
我也會在這媯尼A 也許
And I'll be here, maybe.
歡迎參加訓龍課程
Welcome to dragon training.
沒有回頭路
No turning back.
我真希望我能被燒傷
I hope I get some serious burns.
我只希望肩膀或者後背有一些抓傷
I'm hoping for some mauling, like on my shoulder or lower back.
是啊 傷疤什麼的 很有意思
Yeah, it's only fun if you get a scar out of it.
是啊 這不是鬧著玩的 對嗎? 我喜歡疼痛
Yeah, no kidding, right? Pain, love it.
哦 天哪 誰讓他進來的?
Oh, great, who let him in?
開始吧 最棒的那個人
Lets get started. The recruit who does best,
能得到在全村人面前殺死第一條龍的榮耀!
will win the honor of killing his first dragon in front of the entire village.
Hiccup都已經殺了一條夜煞了 這點小事對他不過是自降身份罷了吧 ?
Hiccup already killed a Night Fury, so does that disqualify him or...?
我能轉到其他的訓練班媔?
Can I transfer to the class with the cool Vikings?
別擔心 你又弱又小 被龍當成目標的概率也低
Don't worry. You're small and you're weak, That will make you a less of a target.
和你這樣的豆芽菜比起來 它們更喜歡一些強壯的維京少年
They'll see you as sick or insane and go after the more Vikinglike teens instead.
在這扇門後面的只是你們以後會遇到的所有龍
Behind these doors are just a few of the
微不足道的幾種
many species you will learn to fight.
致命Nadder  –速度8 防禦16
The Deadly Nadder.   Speed: 8, Armor: 16.
醜陋Zippleback   潛行11速翻倍
The Hideous Zippleback.   11 Stealth times two.
兇魘  –火力15
The Monstrous Nightmare.   Fire Power: 15.
惡龍Terror   8攻12毒
The Terrible Terror.   Attack: 8, Venom: 12.
給我住嘴!
Can you stop that!
還有Gronckle   咬合力8
And the Gronckle.   Jaw Strength: 8.
喂 等一下 你不是應該先教我們嗎?
Woah, woah, wait, aren't you going to teach us first?
我一直堅信實踐是最好的學習方法
I believe in learning on the job.
今天是龍穴生存日 如果你被火球噴個正著 就會當場斃命
Today is about survival. If you get blasted, you're dead.
快! 你們最需要的是什麼?
Quick! What's the first thing you're going to need?
醫生?   加速魔藥?
A doctor?   + 5 Speed?
盾?   盾牌! 盾牌在那
A shield?   Shield. Go.
你們最重要的裝備就是盾牌
Your most important piece of equipment is your shield.
如果只能在劍和盾牌媬鴾@樣
If you must make a choice between a sword or a shield.
盾牌會是你唯一的選擇
Take the shield.
把你的髒手從我的盾牌上拿開!   那堣ㄛO還有一堆嗎?
Get your hands off my shield.   There's like a million shields.
拿那一個 這個上面畫的是一朵花 女孩子喜歡
Take that one. It has a flower on it. Girls like flowers.
哦哦 現在倒是又有了點血跡了
Oops, now this one has blood on it.
Tuffnut Ruffnut 出局
Tuffnut, Ruffnut, your out.
什麼?   什麼?
What?   What?
這個盾牌別有用處 噪音
Those shields are good for another thing. Noise.
用武器敲打盾牌發出噪音 讓龍無法識別目標
Make lots of it and throw off a dragon's aim.
所有的龍能發出的火球都是有限的
All dragons have a limited number of shots.
一條Gronckle有幾個?
How many does a Gronckle have?
5?   不 是6發
Five?   No, six.
沒錯 六發 你們每個人都剛好分到那麼一下
Right, six. Thats one for each of you.
Fishlegs 出局
Fishlegs, out.
Hiccup 躲回去!
Hiccup, get in there!
對了 我把我家的地下室改裝成訓練室了
So anyway, I moved into my parent's basement?
你應該什麼時候過來玩玩 你一直都有在鍛煉的對不對?
You should come by sometimes to work out, You look like you work out.
Snotlout 出局
Snotlout, your done.
我想只剩下你和我了?   不 你還是孤軍奮戰吧
So I guess it's just you and me.   Nope, just you.
還剩下一發
One shot left.
Hiccup啊!
Hiccup!
那麼六發都完了 你這個大香腸 滾回窩堨h睡覺吧
And that's 6. Go back to bed you overgrown sausage.
你還會有其他機會的 別擔心
You'll get another chance. Don't you worry.
記住 一條龍
Remember, a dragon will always...
只會為殺戮而行動
always go for the kill.
那你為什麼沒有這麼做呢?
So why didn't you?
哦 這真是太蠢了
Well this was stupid.
你為什麼不飛走呢?
Why don't you just fly away?
好吧 今天Astrid在訓練場有什麼地方做錯了?
Alright, where did Astrid go wrong in the ring today?
我選錯了翻跟頭的時機 沒有做好 還摔倒了
I mistimed my sommersault dive. It was sloppy. It threw off my reverse tumble.
是 我們都看到了   不 不 你太優秀了 一直這麼出類拔萃
Yeah, we noticed.   No, no you were great. That was so Astrid.
她是對的 你們都應該對自己更加嚴格 那Hiccup又哪堸翕糷F?
She's right. You have to be tough on yourselves. Where did Hiccup go wrong?
呃 他就不應該出現   他該讓自己被吃掉
Uh, he showed up?   He didn't get eaten.
他從來不呆在該呆的地方
He's never where he should be.
謝謝 Astrid 你們需要把這東西背得滾瓜爛熟
Thank you, Astrid. You need to live and breathe this stuff.
飛龍圖鑒  這上面記載了我們對所有龍的一切知識
The Dragon Manual... Everything we know about every dragon we know of.
今天晚上不會有偷襲了 別磨蹭
No attacks tonight. Hurry up.
什麼? 你是說我們要讀書?   我們明明還活著卻要讀書?
Wait? You mean read?   While we're still alive?
我們明明可以直接把龍殺掉 為什麼還要讀這鬼東西?
Why read words when you can just kill the stuff the words tell you stuff about?
哦 這本書我讀了7遍了
Oh, I've read it like 7 times.
有一種水龍會把沸水噴你一臉
There's this water dragon that sprays boiling water at your face
還有這一種 有時候會把自己埋起來一個星期
and there's this other one that buries itself for like a week...
是啊 聽起來不錯 曾經我有機會讀這個書
Yeah, sounds great. There was a chance I was going to read that.
但是現在
But now...
你們讀吧 屠龍的工作交給我就行了
You guys read, I'll go kill something.
喂!
Hey!
看來我們要合用一本書了?   你看吧
So I guess we'll share?   Read it.
嗯 看來只剩下我一個人了? 好吧 嗯 呃  明天見
All mine then? Wow. So, okay. I'll see you uh... tomorrow.
龍族評級
Dragon Classifications
衝擊級 恐怖級 傳說級
Strike Class, Fear Class, Mystery Class.
雷鼓 這種神出鬼沒的孤傲的龍藏逸在深海的洞窟或者黑暗的潮池
Thunder Drum. This reclusive dragon inhabits sea caves and dark tide pools.
一旦被驚動 它們就會發出驚天地泣鬼神的咆哮 方圓數尺之內 全無活口
When startled, the Thunder Drum produces a concussive sound that can kill a man at close range.
危險度高 見者斃命
Extremely dangerous. Kill on sight.
Timberjack: 這種巨型生物的尖銳翅膀能將參天大樹攔腰砍斷
Timberjack: This gigantic creature has razorsharp wings that can slice through fullgrown trees.
危險度高 見者斃命
Extremely dangerous. Kill on sight.
Skulldren: 向敵人亂噴沸水 極度危險
Skulldren: Sprays scalding water on its victim. Extremely dangerous...
Changeling: 哪怕只是剛出生的幼龍也能噴射致命毒液 見者斃命
Changeling: Even newly hatch dragons can spray acid. Kill on sight.
Gronckle Zippleback 還有Skrill
Gronckle, Zippleback, The Skrill,
以及Boneknapper和Whispering Death
Boneknapper, Whispering Death.
燒死 活埋 生吞
Burns its victims. Buries its victims. Chokes its victims.
把內臟全都挖出來
Turns victims inside out.
危險度超高  危險度超高
Extremely dangerous... Extremely dangerous...
見者斃命  見者斃命  見者斃命
Kill on sight... Kill on sight... Kill on sight...
夜煞: 速度未知 大小未知
Night Fury: Speed unknown. Size unknown.
閃電與死神的不潔之子
The unholy offspring of lightning and death itself.
不要嘗試去戰鬥
Never engage this dragon.
唯一的選擇: 躲藏起來 祈禱別被找到
Your only chance: Hide and pray it does not find you.
很近了 我幾乎能聞到它們了
I can almost smell them. They're close.
慢慢來
Steady.
讓我們進去吧   左滿舵
Take us in.   Hard to port.
地獄犬之門啊
The Hell Hounds gate.
左滿舵
Hard to port.
嘿 我剛注意到 書上沒有什麼關於夜煞的資料
Hey, you know, I just happened to notice, the book had nothing on Night Furys.
還有另外的書呢? 或是續集? 也許是僅僅提到?
Is there like another book? or a sequel? Maybe a little Night Fury pamphlet?
注意 Hiccup! 你在搞什麼
Focus Hiccup! You're not even trying.
今天學的是攻擊!
Today is all about attack!
Nadder又輕又快 你必須更輕更快
Nadder's are quick and light on their feet. You be quicker and lighter.
我開始懷疑這種教學方法了
I'm really beginning to question your teaching methods.
找龍的弱點 每條龍都有
Look for its blind spot. Every dragon has one.
找到了 躲好 然後攻擊
Find it. Hide in it, and strike.
你洗澡了嗎?   你不喜歡它 那就快找到盲點躲起來
Do you ever bathe?   You don't like it, then just get your own blind spot.
我給你找一個怎麼樣?
How about I give you one?
盲點 不錯 致命弱點 還得努力
Blind spot, yes. Death spot, notsomuch.
嘿 嘿 那麼怎麼才能接近夜煞呢?
Hey, hey, so how would one sneak up on a Night Fury?
甚至沒有人見到過 活下來做好記錄 現在 快進去!
No one's ever met one, and lived to tell the tale. Now, get in there!
我知道 我的意思是假設
I know, I know but hypothetically...
小心 寶貝 我能處理
Watch out, babe, I'll take care of this.
陽光太刺眼了 Astrid
The sun was in my eyes, Astrid.
你想讓我做什麼? 擋住陽光?
What do you want me to do? Block out the sun?
我可以 但是現在沒時間
I can do that. I don't have time right now.
有人看到過瞌睡龍嗎?   Hiccup!
Has anyone ever seen one napping?   Hiccup!
Hiccup啊!
Hiccup!
在戰場還能談戀愛   她能做得更好
Love on the battlefield.   She could do better.
讓  讓  我為什麼不讓我
L... Let me... why don't you...
喔! 喔! 喔!
Ow! Ow! Ow!
幹得好 Astrid
Well done, Astrid.
這對你來說又是笑話嗎?
Is this some kind of a joke to you?
我們馬上要接過父母的武器 搞清楚你是哪一邊的
Our parent's war is about to become ours. Figure out which side your on.
呃? 你沒有牙
Huh? Toothless.
我能肯定你有
I could of sworn you have...
牙
teeth.
呃 不  不  不
Uh, uh... no, no... no...
我  我沒有更多的了
I... I don't have anymore.
它一扭 咬下了我的一隻手 吞了下去
And with one twist, he took my hand and swallowed it whole.
我看到它臉上的表情 一定在說美味極了
And I saw the look in his face. I was delicious.
它一定回去大肆宣傳了 因為不到一個月
He must have passed the word, because it wasn't a month
另一條咬下了我的一條腿
before another one of them took my leg.
你的手在龍的肚子堣ㄦ|感到奇怪嗎?
Isn't it weird to think that your hand was inside a dragon?
就好比如果你還能控制你的手 你就可以由內攻外
Like, if your mind was still in control of it, you could have killed the dragon from the inside
通過捏爆它的心臟而取勝
by crushing his heart or something.
我此刻真的非常生氣 我發誓
I swear, I'm so angry right now.
要為你那優雅的手和美麗的腿復仇
I'll avenge your beautiful hand and your beautiful foot.
我要親眼目睹自己砍下打的每一條龍的  腿!
I'll chop of the legs of every dragon I fight... with my face!
不 要砍下龍的翅膀和尾巴
No. It's the wings and the tails you really want.
如果它飛不了了 它也活不久了
If it can't fly, it can't get away.
一條不能飛的龍就是臨死的龍
A downed dragon is a dead dragon.
是   是
Yeah.   Yeah.
好了 我要去睡覺了
Alright, I'm off to bed.
你們也早點休息啊 明天還有大玩意兒
You should be too. Tomorrow we get to the big boys.
我們慢慢地逼近兇魘
Slowly but surely, making our way up to Monstruous Nightmare.
但是誰能夠得到殺死龍的榮耀呢?   一定是我 命中注定的
But who'll win the honor of killing it?   It's gonna be me. It's my destiny. See?
你媽媽同意你文身?   這不是文身 這是胎記
Your mom let you get a tattoo?   It's not a tattoo. It's a birth mark.
好吧 我從出生就和你在一起 但是從沒有見到過
Okay, I've been stuck with you since birth and that was never there before.
是的 這是胎記 因為你從不看我的左邊
Yes, it was. You've just never seen me to the left side until now.
嘿 無牙 我拿早飯來了
Hey, Toothless. I brought breakfast.
我希望  我希望你飢腸轆轆了
I hope... I hope you're hungry.
好吧 這確實很噁心
Okay, that's disgusting.
我拿來了一些鮭魚 冰島鱈魚 還有鰻魚
I got some salmon, some nice Icelandic cod, and a whole smoked eel.
不 不 不 不  不  好吧
No, no, no, no... no... Okay.
是 我也不喜歡鰻魚
Yeah, I don't really like eel much either.
就是這樣 這可是好東西 別管我
That's it. That's the good stuff. Aah, don't you mind me.
我馬上回來 忙我自己的事情
I'll just be back here, minding my own business.
沒事的
It's okay...
好的 好的
Okay, okay...
好 這不糟糕 起作用了
Okay, that's not too bad. It works.
不 不 不 不 不 !
No, no, no, no, no, no...!
哦天哪  成功了!
Oh my... It's working!
是的 是的 我做到了
Yes, yes, I did it.
今天的重點是團隊合作
Today, is about teamwork.
如果龍頭濕了就不能點火了
Now, a wet dragon head can't light its fire.
醜陋Zippleback非常麻煩
The Hideous Zippleback is extra tricky.
一個頭放出氣體 另一個頭點燃
One head breathes gas. The other head lights it.
你們的任務是分清楚頭
Your job is to know which is which.
剃刀般鋒利的牙齒 對獵物注入毒液幫助消化
Razorsharp serrated teeth, and injects venom for predigestion.
喜歡伏擊 壓碎敵人
Prefers ambush attack, crushing its victims.
你就不能消停會兒嗎?!
Will you please stop that?!
如果龍露出它的任意一張臉 我就要
If that dragon shows either of his faces, I'm gonna...
那!
There!
嘿 是我 白癡!
Hey, it's us, idiots!
你的屁股越來越大 我們還以為是龍呢
Your butts are getting bigger we thought you were a dragon.
有個龍屁股也沒什麼不好
Not that there's anything wrong with a dragonass fig...
等等
Wait...
哦! 哦 我受傷了! 我受傷了!
Oh! Oh, I'm hurt! I am very much hurt!
生存的機會越來越渺茫了
Chances of survival are dwindling into single digits now.
哦! 搞錯頭了
Oh! Wrong head.
Fishlegs啊!
Fishlegs!
快 Hiccup!
Now Hiccup!
哦 來吧
Aww, come on...
Hiccup啊!
Hiccup!
後退 後退 後退!
Back, back, back!
別讓我再說一次!
Now don't you make me tell you again!
好 這才是啊 回到籠子堨h!
Yes, that's right. Back into your cage!
好好反省你做了什麼
Now think about what you've done.
好 嗯嗯 可以了吧?
Okay, sooo, were we done?
我還有事要做 呃  明天見
'Cause I have some things I need to uh... Yep, I'll see you tomorrow.
嘿!
Hey!
那是怎麼回事?   你怎麼做到的?
What was that?   How did you do that?
我把斧頭忘在訓練場了 你們先走
I left my axe back in the ring. You guys go on ahead.
我等下趕上來
I'll catch up with you.
見識一下惡龍Terror
Meet the Terrible Terror.
哈! 它的個頭只有我的
Ha! It's like the size of my...
哦! 滾開!
Oooh! Get it off!
哦 我受傷了! 疼死我了!
Oh, I'm hurt! I am very much hurt!
哇喔! 他比你厲害多了
Wow! He's better than you ever were.
什麼?
What?
哦 好吧
Ooh, great.
Hiccup啊
Hiccup.
Hiccup? 你在嗎?
Hiccup? Are you in there?
Astrid 嘿 Astrid 你好 Astrid
Astrid, hey. Hi, Astrid. Hi Astrid. Hi Astrid
我一般不在乎別人在做什麼 但你的舉止有點詭異
I normally don't care what people do, but you're acting weird.
呃 有點神秘
Well, weirder.
嗯 我相信 你們至少找到了老巢吧?
Well, I trust you found the nest at least?
連影都沒見著
Not even close.
很好
Excellent.
我希望 你能把我比下去
I hope you had a little more success than me.
嗯 說到成就 如果你是指沒有了家教方面的麻煩
Well, if by success, you mean that your parenting troubles are over with...
那麼 是的
then, yes.
祝賀你 Stoick! 大家都感到很寬慰
Congratulations Stoick! Everyone is so relieved.
舊的不去 新的不來 是吧?
Out with the old, and in with the new, right?
沒有人會想念那個討厭鬼
No one will miss that old nuisance.
村子堨蕊}派對在慶祝呢
The village is throwing a party to celebrate.
他出去了?
He's gone?
嗯 是的 多數下午都有出去 但是何必責怪他呢?
Um, yeah, most afternoons, but who can blame him?
我是說 名人的生活也不簡單
I mean, the life of a celebrity is very rough.
在村子 他總是被一群人追捧 讓他寸步難行
He can barely walk through the village without being swarmed by his new fans.
Hiccup?   沒有人能想到 啊?
Hiccup?   Who would have thought it, eh?
對付那些怪獸 他有一套
He has this way with the beasts.
好了 夥計 我現在得慢慢來
Okay there, bud, were gonna take this nice and slow.
來吧 來吧 三號部位 不 四號部位
Here we go. Here we go. Position three, no, four.
好了 是時候了 好戲上場了
Alright, it's go time. It's go time.
加油 夥計 加油 夥計
Come on, buddy. Come on, buddy.
太好了 成功了!
Yes, it works!
抱歉!
Sorry!
我錯了
That's my fault.
嗯 好的 我正在努力 四號部位 呃 是三號
Yeah, yeah, I'm on it. Position four, uh, three.
太好了! 寶貝!
Yeah! Go baby!
噢 太神奇了! 這風在我
Oh, this is amazing! The wind in my...
小抄!
cheat sheet!
不要!
Stop!
不!
No!
噢 糟了! 噢 天哪!
Oh, Gosh! Oh, God!
哦 不!
Oh no!
好了 你得讓自己控制方向!
Alright. Okay. You gotta kinda angle yourself!
好了 不 不 不  朝我飛過來
Okay. No, no, no... Come back down towards me.
再近一點  啊!
Come back down... Oww!
太棒了!
Yeah!
不是吧
Come on...
噢 我不用 謝謝了
Uh, no thanks. I'm good.
體內不夠耐火啊 是嗎?
Not so fireproof on the inside, are you?
來吧
Here you go.
我們完全誤解你們了
Everything we know about you guys is wrong.
爸爸 你回來了!
Dad, you're back!
Gobber不在這兒 所以
Gobber's not here, so...
我知道
I know.
我是來找你的
I came looking for you.
是嗎?   你一直鬼鬼祟祟的
You did?   You've been keeping secrets.
我有這樣嗎?
I have?
你覺得你可以藏多久呢?
Just how long did you think you could hide it from me?
我  我不知道你在
I... I don't know what you...
這個島上發生的一切 我都瞭如指掌
Nothing happens on this island, without me hearing about it.
噢?
Oh?
所以 讓我們來說  說那條龍
So, lets talk... about that dragon
噢 天啊
Oh Gods...
爸爸 我很抱歉 我
Dad, I'm so sorry. I...
我本打算告訴你的 只是我不知道該怎麼
I was going to tell you, I just didn't know how to uh...
你  你不擔心了?   什麼啊? 這正是我期待的!
You... you're not upset?   What? I was hoping for this!
啊 你?   相信我
Ah, you were?   And believe me...
只會越來越好 就等你首次取出一條Nadder的內臟
It only gets better. Just wait till you spill a Nadder's guts for the first time...
用矛取下Gronckle的首級
and mount your first Gronckle head on a spear.
多棒的感覺啊! 這就是我所期待的你 孩子
What feeling! You really had me going there, son.
過去的那麼多年 維京人博克族中最差勁的人
All those years of the worst Viking Berk has ever seen.
主神啊 真不容易啊 我幾乎對你不抱期望了
Odin, it was rough. I almost gave up on you.
而你卻一直緊隨我之後
And all the while you were holding out on me.
噢 萬能的托爾神啊!
Oh, Thor almighty!
鑒於你在場上的優秀表現
With you doing so well in the ring...
我們終於有了共同話題
we finally have something to talk about.
我 呃 我給你帶來了一個東西
I uh, I brought you something...
讓你免受傷害
to keep you safe in the ring.
哇 謝謝
Wow, thanks.
你母親希望你戴上它
Your mother would wanted you to have it.
這是用她的半個胸甲鑄造的
It's half of her breast plate.
我們的是一套 你要知道 讓她  更靠近我們
Matching set. Keeps her... Keeps her close, you know.
戴上它吧 會你無比自豪的 這是你應得的
Wear it proudly. You deserve it.
你履行了你的諾言
You've held your end of the deal.
我得上床睡覺了
I should really get to bed.
是的 好的 行 聊得很開心   是的
Yes, good, okay, good talk.   Yeah...
我會去找你的 好了 謝謝你來看我
I'll see you back at the house. Great. Thanks for stopping by and...
呃 還有  胸帽   我希望你會喜歡 呃  這個頭盔
the uh... breast hat.   I hope you like the, umm... the hat.
嗯 晚安
Well, good night.
別擋道 勝利是我的!
Stay out of my way. I'm winning this thing!
好的 請吧 當然可以
Good. Please. By all means.
就這次了 一次成功!
This time! This time for sure!
不! 不 妖娘養的 好吃懶做的飯桶 !
No! No, sonofa half troll, rateating munch bucket...!
等等! 等等!
Wait! Wait.
那麼  待會見哦
So... later.
噢 噢! 還沒呢!   我快遲到了
Oh, oh! Not so fast!   I'm kinda late for...
什麼! 到底是遲到什麼?
What! Late for what, exactly?
好了 安靜下 前輩們已經做好決定了
Okay, quiet down. The Elder has decided.
小傢伙 你做到了! 你做到了 Hiccup!
Boy, you've done it! You've done it, Hiccup!
你將殺死那條龍!
You get to kill the dragon!
那才是我的兒子!
That's my boy!
是啊! 是的 我迫不及待了 我太
Yeah! Yes, I can't wait. I am so...
走吧 我們要上路了
leaving. We're Leaving.
我們收拾東西吧
Let's pack up.
貌似你和我要一起度個假
Looks like you and me are taking a little vacation.
沒有盡頭的假期
Forever.
啊 老兄啊
Awww, man.
什麼啊 ? 啊 你  在這幹什麼呢?
What the...? Uh, w... what are you doing here?
我想知道事情的真相
I want to know what's going on.
沒有人可以做的跟你一樣好
No one just get as good as you do.
特別是  你
Especially... you.
快說   我  我
Start talking.   I... I...
是不是有人跟你一起訓練?
Are you training with someone?
訓練? 我沒有
Training? I didn't...
最好沒有
It better not involve this.
我知道 這看上去很不厚道 但你看 這是
I know, this looks really bad but you see, this is...
你說對了 你說對了 說對了 我  我再也不想扯謊了
You're right. You're right. You're right. I... I'm through with the lies.
我一直在做  裝備!
I've been making... outfits!
所以 被你發現了 現在大家也該知道了
So, you got me. It's time everyone knew.
把我拖回去吧 來吧 來啊
Drag me back. Go ahead. Here we go.
啊 你為什麼這樣?
Oww. Why would you do that?
這是騙子的下場!
That's for the lies!
而這  是關於其他事情的了斷!
And that's... for everything else!
噢 老兄
Oh man.
趴下!
Get down!
快跑! 快跑!
Run! Run!
不! 不! 沒事 不要緊 她是一個朋友
No! No! It's okay. It's okay. She's a friend.
你剛剛嚇到它了
You just scared him.
我嚇到它了?
I scared him?
它是誰?
Who is him?
Astrid 這是無牙 無牙 這是Astrid
Astrid, Toothless. Toothless, Astrid.
噠噠噠  我們死定了
Dut, da da... We're dead.
哇啊 哇啊 哇啊 你要去哪?
Woah, woah woah. Where do you think your going?
噢 主神啊! 不要啊 噢 這
Oh, great Odin! Don't. Oh, this is...
Hiccup 讓我下去!
Hiccup, get me down from here!
我必須給我一個解釋的機會
You have to give me a chance to explain.
你說什麼我都不會聽的!
I am not listening to anything you have to say!
那我不說話 讓我演示給你看
Then I won't speak. Just let me show you.
拜託了 Astrid
Please, Astrid.
快放我下來!
Now get me down!
無牙 輕輕地飛下去
Toothless, down. Gently.
看見了吧 沒什麼可怕的
See, nothing to be afraid of.
無牙?
Toothless?
你怎麼了? 你這個惡龍!
What is wrong with you? Bad dragon!
它 呃 它一般情況是不會這樣的
He's uh, he's not usually like this.
噢 不!
Oh, no!
無牙 你要幹什麼? 我得討她喜歡!
Toothless, what are you doing? We need her to like us!
你還打轉轉!
And now he's spinning!
太感謝你了 你這沒用的爬行動物!
Thank you for nothing you useless reptile!
好了 我很抱歉 抱歉 只要把我放下去就好了
Okay, I am sorry, I'm sorry. Just get me off of this thing.
好吧 我承認 這實在是太酷了
Alright, I admit it. This is pretty cool.
太神奇了 它太了不起了
It's amazing. He's amazing.
然後呢?
So what now?
Hiccup 下周就是你的最終考核了!
Hiccup, your final exam is tomorrow!
你知道 你必須得殺死一條
You know your gonna have to kill a...
殺死一條龍
kill a dragon...
不用你提醒
Don't remind me.
無牙 怎麼了?
Toothless, what happening?
哇哦 是什麼?
Whoa, what is it?
趴下!
Get down!
怎麼回事?   我不知道
What's going on?   I don't know.
無牙 你得把我們從這帶出去 夥計
Toothless, you gotta get us out of here, bud.
它們貌似在搬運獵物
It looks like they're hauling in their kill.
難不成我們也成獵物了?
What does that make us?
我爸爸是不可能找到這堛
What my dad wouldn't give to find this.
噢 真是令人欣慰 原來我們的糧食都傾倒在這堣F
Oh, it's satisfying to know that all of our food has been dumped down a hole.
它們自己沒有吃掉
They're not eating any of it.
那是什  什麼?
What... was that?
好了 夥計 我們現在必須離開這堣F 快!
Alright, bud, we gotta get out of here. Now!
不 不 完全是講得通的 這就像一個巨大的蜂巢
No, no, it totally makes sense. It's like a giant beehive.
它們就是勞工 而那就是它們的女王
They're the workers, and that's their queen.
它控制著它們 我們現在去找你爸爸
It controls them. Let's find your dad.
不 不
No, no.
不 現在還不行 他們會殺了無牙的
No. Not yet. They'll kill Toothless.
Astrid 我們得仔細想清楚
Astrid, we have to think this through, carefully.
Hiccup 我剛剛發現了一個龍穴
Hiccup, we just discovered the dragon's nest.
這可是我們維京人定居此地以來一直尋求的
The thing we've been after since Vikings first sailed here.
而你卻想保守秘密?
And you want to keep it secret?
為了保護你的寵物龍? 你說真的嗎?
To protect your pet, dragon? Are you serious?
是的
Yes.
好吧 那我們該怎麼做呢?
Okay. Then what do we do?
給我一晚上的時間 我會想出辦法的
Just give me until tomorrow. I'll figure something out.
好的
Okay...
這是綁架我的懲罰
That's for kidnapping me.
這是  其他所有事情的報答
That's for... everything else.
你在看什麼?
What are you looking at?
嗯 我再次拋頭露面了
Well, I can show my face in public again.
如果在幾周前 有人告訴我
If someone had told me that in a few short weeks
Hiccup會從一個  呃 成為一個Hiccup
Hiccup will go from... well being... uh... Hiccup,
並在訓練中勇爭第一
to placing first in dragon training.
嗯 以免他瘋言瘋語 我會把他綁在桅桿上 然後將他遣送出境
Well, I would have tied him to a mast and shipped him off. For fear he'd gone mad.
而你們也知道
And you know it.
但是 現在
But, here we are.
沒人能比我更驚訝或者更自豪
And no ones more surprised or more proud than I am.
今天 我的兒子成為了一名真正的維京勇士!
Today my boy becomes a Viking!
今天他成為了我們中的一員!
Today he becomes one of us!
當心那條龍
Be careful with that dragon.
並不是龍讓我擔憂
It's not the dragon I'm worried about.
你打算怎麼辦?
What are you going to do?
平息這一切
Put an end to this.
我得試一試
I have to try.
Astrid 如果我遭逢不測 千萬別讓他們找到無牙
Astrid, if something goes wrong, just make sure they don't find Toothless.
我會的 你得向我保證你會平平安安的
I will, just promise me it won't go wrong.
時間到了 Hiccup
It's time, Hiccup.
放倒它們
Knock 'em dead.
我會選鐵錘
I'd have gone for the hammer.
我準備好了
I'm ready.
加油 Hiccup 給它點顏色看看!
Go on Hiccup, give it to him!
他在幹什麼?
What is he doing?
沒關係 沒事的
It's okay, it's okay.
我並非他們那類人
I'm not one of them.
他在想什麼?
What's he thinking?
停止打鬥!
Stop the fight!
不! 我需要大家來見證
No! I need you all to see this.
它們並非我們想的那樣
They're not what we think they are.
我們不必殺死它們
We don't have to kill them.
我說了 停止打鬥!
I said stop the fight!
讓開 別擋道!
Out of my way!
Hiccup啊!
Hiccup!
這邊!
This way!
夜煞!
Night Fury!
好了 無牙 快走! 離開這
Alright, Toothless. Go! Get out of here.
走 快走!
Go, go!
不 爸爸! 爸爸 它不會傷害你們的!
No, dad! Dad, he won't hurt you!
無牙 停下!
Toothless, stop!
不 不!
No. No!
捉住它!
Get him!
不不 求求你們 別傷害它
No, no, please. Just don't hurt him
拜託 別傷害它
Please. Don't hurt him
和其他的關到一起
Put it with the others.
我早該明白
I should have known.
我早該注意到這些跡象
I should have seen the signs.
爸爸?   我們達成了協議!
Dad?   We had a deal!
我知道! 我們說好了 但是那是在我  哦 全都被搞得一團糟
I know! We did, but that was before I... Oh, it's all so messed up.
那麼鬥獸場上的一切  是一場騙局? 一個謊言?
So everything in that ring... A trick? A lie?
我搞砸了 之前我就該告訴你
I screwed up. I should have told you before now.
都是我的錯 衝我發火吧 但是求求你 就是不要傷害無牙
Take this out on me, be mad at me, but please, just don't hurt Toothless.
那條龍? 那就是你擔心的?
The dragon? That's what you're worried about?
而不是幾乎被你殺害的人?
Not the people you almost killed?
它只是在保護我! 它並不危險
He was just protecting me! He's not dangerous.
它們已經殺了我們幾百號人!
They've killed hundreds of us!
我們也殺了它們數以千計的同類 它們是自衛 僅此而已
And we've killed thousands of them. They defend themselves, that's all.
它們襲擊我們也是萬不得已
They raid us because they have to.
如果它們沒帶回足夠的食物 自己就會被吃掉
If they don't bring enough food back, they'll be eaten themselves.
它們的島上還有別的生物 是一種像龍的
There's something else on their island, dad. It's a dragonlike...
它們的島? 所以說 你去過它們的巢穴?
Their island? So, you've been to the nest?
我說了巢穴嗎?   你怎麼找到的?
Did I say nest?   How did you find it?
不不 不是我 是無牙找到的 只有龍才找得到那個島
No, no, I didn't. Toothless did. Only a dragon can find the island.
不不 爸 不要 求求你 那堣ㄛO你想的那樣
No, no, dad, no please. It's not what you think.
你不知道你會面臨什麼 那是你前所未見的
You don't know what your up against. It's like nothing you've ever seen.
爸爸 求求你 我向你保證 你不可能獲勝!
Dad, please, I promise you. You can't win this one!
爸爸 不!
Dad, no!
這輩子 你就不能聽我一次嗎!
For once in your life, would you please just listen to me!
你已經成為它們中的一份子
You've thrown your lot in with them.
你不是一名維京勇士
You're not a Viking.
你不是我兒子!
You're not my son!
備船!
Ready the ships!
啟航!
Set sail!
向地獄犬之門前進
We head for Hell Hounds gate.
帶我們歸巢吧 惡魔
Lead us home, devil.
真是一團糟 你肯定感到恐懼
It's a mess. You must feel horrible.
你已經失去了一切 你的父親 族人和最好的朋友
You've lost everything. Your father, your tribe, your best friend.
謝謝你的總結
Thank you for summing that up.
為什麼當我在樹林媯o現那條龍時 沒有殺了它呢?
Why couldn't I've killed that dragon, when I found him the woods?
那樣可能對大伙更好
Would've been better for everyone.
嗯 其他人可能會這麼做
Yep, the rest of us would have done it.
那麼 為什麼你不這樣做?
So, why didn't you?
為什麼不這樣做?
Why didn't you?
我不知道 我做不到
I don't know. I couldn't.
這不算回答   為什麼突然間 這對你這麼重要?
That's not an answer.   Why is this so important to you all of a sudden?
因為我想記住你說的話 快說
Because I want to remember what you say, right now.
啊 因為是愛  我是個懦夫 我很軟弱
Ah, for the love of... I was coward, I was weak.
我不願去殺龍!
I wouldn't kill a dragon!
你剛剛說 你不願意殺龍?
You said wouldn't that time?
無論如何 我不願意!
Whatever, I wouldn't!
300年了 我是第一個不願殺龍的維京人
300 years and I'm the first Viking who wouldn't kill a dragon.
卻是第一個騎龍的
First to ride one though.
所以?
So?
我不願殺它 因為它看起來和我一樣受到了驚嚇
I wouldn't kill him because he looked as frightened as I was.
我看見它 就像看到了自己
I looked at him and I saw myself.
我確信它現在很恐懼
I bet he's really frightened now.
那你打算怎麼辦?
What are you gonna do about it?
可能會做些蠢事
Probably something stupid.
很好 但是你已經做了
Good, but you've already done that.
那麼做些瘋狂的事吧!
Then something crazy!
這才像話
That's more like it.
測量船距! 保持在聽力範圍之內
Sound your positions! Stay within earshot.
聽著 Stoick 我剛剛偷聽到有人 嗯 你明白
Listen, Stoick, I was overhearing some of the men just now and well, you know...
有人好奇 我們這次來這的目的是什麼?
some of them are wondering what it is we're up to here?
當然不是我 你知道你一向是個有計劃的人
Not me of course. I know you are always the man with the plan.
但是有些人 不是我 想知道實際上是否有個計劃
But some, not me, are wondering if there is in fact a plan at all...
還有 計劃大致是什麼?
and what it might be?
找到它們的巢穴 並摧毀它
Find the nest and take it.
當然 讓它們四處逃竄 老一輩維京勇士沒有取勝 應該是小菜一碟吧
Of course. Send them running. The old Viking fallback. Nice and simple.
讓開
Step aside.
向左轉舵
Head to port.
如果你打算被吃掉 我更願意去陪著Gronckle
If you're planning on getting eaten, I'd definitely go with the Gronckle.
如果你明智地選擇 從世界上最致命的武器那尋求幫助
You were wise to seek help from the world's most deadly weapon.
那就是我
It's me.
我愛這個計劃!   我不
I love this plan!   I didn't...
你太瘋狂了 我喜歡
You're crazy. I like that.
那麼 有什麼計劃?
So, what is the plan?
形勢不妙啊
That's not very encouraging.
哦 我很好奇它要去哪
Oh, I was wondering where that went.
保持警惕 準備武器
Stay low, and ready your weapons.
我們到了
We're here.
等等 你要干  ?!
Wait, what are you... ?!
沒問題  沒問題
It's okay... It's okay.
你去哪?
Where are you going?
你還需要點東西 幫助你繼續下去
You're gonna need something to help you hold on.
當我們砸開這座山時 所有畜生都會傾巢而出
When we crack this mountain open, all hell is gonna break loose.
那會嚇得尿褲子 好在我多帶了幾條
In my undies. Good thing I brought extras.
無論結局如何 一切將在今天結束
No matter how this ends, it ends today.
就這樣?
Is that it?
我們成功了!
We've done it!
還沒完!
This isn't over!
整隊 團結一致!
Form your ranks. Pull together!
撤退!
Get clear!
這是雷神托爾的鬍鬚嗎 ! 那是什麼?
Beards of Thor...! What is that?
主神奧汀(托爾之父) 救救我們吧!
Odin, help us!
彈弩!   發射!
Catapults!   Fire!
上船!   不 不!
Get to the ships!   No, nooo!
不是那艘    我傻了
Not that one...   I was a fool.
帶大伙去島嶼的另一側
Lead the men to the far side of the island.
Gobber 和大家一起走
Gobber, go with the men.
我想我決定留下來 以防你想做什麼瘋狂的事
I think I'll stay, just in case you're thinking of doing something crazy.
如果我讓那東西有目標可尋 那麼還能爭取到一些時間
I can buy them a few minutes if I give that thing something to hunt for.
那我可以讓時間翻倍
Then I can double that time.
到這來!   哦 不 到這來!
Here!   Oh, no. Here!
來打我啊!   不 打我!
Fight me!   No, me!
Ruff Tuff 小心你們的後面!
Ruff, Tuff, watch your backs!
前進 Fishlegs!
Move, Fishlegs!
看我們! 我們騎著龍! 我們騎著龍! 我們所有人!
Look at us! We're on dragons! We're on dragons! All of us!
每個維京勇士都是固執頑強的 就像你一樣
Every bit the bullheaded stubborn Viking you ever were.
Fishlegs 說明詳情!   好的
Fishlegs, break it down!   Okay.
顱骨和尾部覆有厚重鎧甲 有助於猛擊和壓碎物體 要閃避這兩處
Heavily armored skull and tail made for bashing and crushing. Steer clear of both.
小眼睛和大鼻孔 它主要依靠聽覺和嗅覺
Small eyes, large nostrils. Relies on hearing and smell.
好的 Lout Legs 飛至它的盲區 製造噪音給它混淆試聽
Okay, Lout, Legs, hang in its blind spot. Make some noise. Keep it confused.
Ruff Tuff 查明它是否有射擊次數限制 並激怒它
Ruff, Tuff, find out if it has a shot limit. Make it mad.
這是我的拿手好戲!   什麼時候開始?
That's my specialty!   Since when?
大家都知道 我最讓人惱火 看
Everyone knows I'm more irritating, see.
就照我說的去做 我會盡快回來
Just do what I told you. I'll be back as soon as I can.
別擔心 我們為你做掩護!
Don't worry! We got it covered!
好!
Yeah!
傻子!   蠢貨!
Fool!   Butto!
再見 白癡!
Bye, ya Grendel!
呃 這東西沒有盲區!
Um, this thing doesn't have a blind spot!
那!
There!
去幫其他人!
Go help the others!
好的 等等 等等
Okay, hold on. Hold on.
起作用了!   嗯 奏效了!
It's working!   Yeah, it's working!
我已經沒法控制Gronckle了! Snotlout 看你的了!
I've lost power on the Gronckle! Snotlout, do something!
我沒事!
I'm okay!
勉強沒事
Less okay.
我不能錯失良機! 怎麼樣 夥計? 覺得眼睛埵釭F西?
I can't miss! What's wrong, buddy? You got something in your eye?
是的 你是維京勇士!
Yeah, you're the Viking!
嗚啊!
Woah!
爸爸?
Dad?
你成功了 夥計!
You got it, buddy!
Hiccup啊!
Hiccup!
對不起
I'm sorry...
我為  為所有事道歉
for... for everything.
嗯  我也是
Yeah... me too.
你不必到那去
You don't have to go up there.
我們是維京勇士 這是滲入進骨子堛澈_險精神
We're Vikings. It's an occupational hazard...
你是我兒子 我為你驕傲
I'm proud to call you my son.
謝謝 爸爸
Thanks, Dad.
他來了!
He's up!
帶Snotlout離開!
Get Snotlout outta there!
我騎著它!   我先騎的!
I'm on it!   I'm on it first!
嘿 讓我騎!
Hey, let me drive!
別推我!   我拔光你的牙!
Don't push me!   I'll push your teeth out!
你知道嗎 我無法相信這成功了
You know, I can't believe that worked.
夜煞!   趴下!
Night Fury!   Get down!
你抓住她了嗎?
Did you get her?
走!
Go!
這傢伙有翅膀 好吧 讓我們看看它會不會用!
This thing has wings. Okay, let's see if it can use them!
你覺得它飛過嗎?
You think that did it?
嗯 它會飛
Well, he can fly.
好吧 無牙 沒時間了! 來吧 夥計!
Okay, Toothless, time to disappear! Come on, bud!
它來了!
Here it comes!
當心!
Watch out!
好吧 時間到 看看這樣是否有效
Okay, time's up. Let's see if this works.
來吧! 這就是你全部的本事嗎?
Come on! Is that the best you can do?
陪著我 夥計 我們沒問題 只要再堅持一會兒
Stay with me, buddy. We're good. Just a little bit longer.
堅持住 無牙 小心!
Hold, Toothless. Now!
不  不!
No... No!
Hiccup! Hiccup啊!
Hiccup! Hiccup!
兒子!
Son!
Hiccup啊!
Hiccup!
哦 兒子!
Oh son!
我一手造成的
I did this.
對  對不起
I'm s... I'm so sorry.
Hiccup啊!
Hiccup!
他還活著! 你讓他重生!
He's alive! You brought him back alive!
謝謝你  救了我的兒子
Thank you... for saving my son.
呃 你知道 救了他的大部分
Well, you know, most of him.
嘿 無牙
Hey, Toothless.
我也很高興見到你 夥計
Happy to see you too, buddy.
啊 什麼  呃  我  在家
Aawww, what... uh... I'm... in my house
你在我家
You're in my house.
我爸爸知道你在這嗎?
Does my dad know you're here?
嗯 什麼 哦 好吧  好吧
Uh, what, oh, okay... okay.
無牙 不 無牙! 啊 別這樣
Toothless, no. Toothless! Aw, come on.
好吧 謝謝 夥計
Okay. Thanks, bud.
無牙 留在這
Toothless, stay here.
大家來吧 準備好! 抓緊 我們走!
C'mon guys. Get ready! Hold on tight. Here we go!
什麼?
What?
我懂了 我死了
I knew it. I'm dead.
不 但是你給了它最棒的一擊
No, but you give it your best shot.
那麼 你覺得怎麼樣?
So, what do you think?
嘿 看 是Hiccup!
Hey look, it's Hiccup!
Hiccup啊!
Hiccup!
事實證明 我們更需要的是  這樣的你
It turns out, all we needed was a little more of... this.
你剛指的是我的全部?
You just gestured to all of me?
嗯 你的大部分 那小部分是我的作品
Well, most of you. That bit's my handiwork.
加入了一點Hiccup的光芒 你覺得怎麼樣?
With a little Hiccup flare thrown in. You think that'll do?
我可能需要做幾次微調
I might make a few tweaks.
這一下  是因為你嚇到我了
That's... for scaring me.
什麼  什麼 總要這樣嗎? 因為
What... what, is it always going to be this way? Because...
我會習慣的
I could get used to it.
歡迎回家
Welcome home.
夜煞!   趴下!
Night Fury!   Get down!
你準備好了嗎?
You ready?
這堿O博克島
This is Berk...
一年下九個月的雪 另三個月下冰雹
It snows nine months of the year and hails the other three.
任何生長在這的食物都堅硬無味
Any food that grows here is tough and tasteless.
生長在這的人們更是堅韌不拔
The people that grow here are even more so.
唯一的好處就是寵物
The only upsides are the pets.
當別的地方飼養小馬或者鸚鵡時
While other places have ponies or parrots...
我們卻擁有
We have...
龍
Dragons.